Prangan Ghosh

Full Stack Developer

A motivated Full Stack Developer with **3 years** of experience and Expert in **Node**, **React JS**, **Javascript**, and **SQL Server**, having worked on **5+ projects** with both front and back end programming. Also responsible for developing and designing front end web architecture.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cargo Flash Info Tech., Gurgaon Full Stack Developer

Nov 2021 - Nov 2023

- Developed Cargo Tracking Systems using React, Angular, .NET, SQL, and C#.Enhancing user experience and increasing tracking accuracy by 25%, leading to a 15% boost in customer satisfaction.
- Developing front end website architecture, APIs and Creating servers and databases for functionality.
- Increasing monthly active users by 60% and decreasing server response time by 25%
- Designing user interactions on web pages and Excellent verbal communication skills, Good problem solving skills and Attention to detail.

Cargo Flash Info Tech., Gurgaon

ML Engineer

May 2021 - Nov 2021

- Acquired 1 year of professional experience in Python programming.
- Managed 2 advanced data analysis, machine learning, and Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) projects.
- Engineered and trained sophisticated models using: Random Forest algorithm XGBoost classification algorithm.
- Achieving: Accuracy: 95% for Random Forest
- 97% for XGBoost AUC score: 0.98 for XGBoost.
- Conducted Rigorous model prediction accuracy analysis using: Classification Reports, Confusion Matrix and AUC score.

PROJECTS

nGEN RMS - Revenue Management System

- Enabled 50+ worldwide airline carriers to anticipate & manage their resources and product price along with services.
- Web designed and launched revenue management systems for cargo companies, improving net functionality by 25% within 6 months.
- Tech Stack -React JS, .NET Core 3.1, SQL Server.

Target Planning System - CRUD and Dynamic Pricing

 The next-generation Target Planning System helps airlines and enterprises to set annual, monthly, and quarterly targets and monitor a pragmatic approach for managing sales and targets.

- Gurugram, INDIA (122002)
- +91 8383007824
- pranganghosh7@gmail.com
- <u>LinkedIn</u>
- Portfolio website
- Github

SKILLS

React js.

Node js.

JavaScript ES6

HTML

CSS₃

.NET Core

C#

MS SQL

TypeScript

Angular 12

Python

EDUCATION

Manav Rachna Int. University

B-Tech in Computer Science Engineering

Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

OTHER

- Certified Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Developer
- Volunteer (3 hours/week) at the Robin Hood Army foundation(RHA)
- Helping to redistribute surplus food from restaurants and the community to serve less fortunate people.
- Management skill and Organizational skill

Languages

- English
- Hindi

- Resource management, Dynamic pricing, Service management.
- Tech Stack Node js. , React js. , SQL Server.

• Spanish (Beginner level)

OctoGo Reservation System , Crud Form for User Details

- The OctoGo Reservation Form for User Details is an Angular-based component that allows users to enter their personal information for making reservations.
- It provides a user-friendly and intuitive interface for capturing and validating user data, ensuring a smooth and efficient reservation process
- Tech Stack Angular , .NET Core , SQL Server.